Never blend in.
Milk is a history, drama film directed by Gus Van Sant.
The true story of Harvey Milk, the first openly gay
man ever elected to public office.
In San Francisco in the late 1970s, Harvey Milk becomes an activist for gay rights and inspires others
to join him in his fight for equal rights that should be available to all Americans.
Harvey Milk, played by Sean Penn.
Cleve Jones, played by Emile Hirsch.
Dan White, played by Josh Brolin.
Jack Lira, played by Diego Luna.
Scott Smith, played by James Franco.
Anne Kronenberg, played by Alison Pill.
Milk is a 2008 American biographical drama film based on the life of gay rights activist and politician Harvey Milk, who was the first
openly gay man to be elected to public office in California, as a member of the San Francisco Board of Supervisors.
Directed by Gus Van Sant and written by Dustin Lance Black, the film stars Sean Penn as
Milk, alongside Emile Hirsch, Josh Brolin, Diego Luna, and James Franco.
Attempts to put Milk's life to film followed a 1984 documentary of his life and the aftermath of his assassination, titled The Times of Harvey Milk, which was loosely based upon Randy Shilts's 1982 biography,
The Mayor of Castro Street (the film won the Academy Award for Best Documentary Feature for 1984, and was awarded Special Jury Prize at the first Sundance Film Festival, among other awards).
Various scripts were considered in the early 1990s, but projects
fell through for different reasons, until 2007.
Much of Milk was filmed on Castro Street and other locations in San
Francisco, including Milk's former storefront, Castro Camera.
The film was released to critical acclaim and grossed $54 million worldwide.
It earned numerous accolades from film critics and guilds for Penn's and Brolin's performances, Van Sant's directing, and Black's screenplay, it received eight Oscar
nominations at the 81st Academy Awards, including Best Picture and went on to win two: Best Actor for Penn and Best Original Screenplay for Black.
The film explores themes of california, election campaign,
politics, homophobia, san francisco, california.
The tone is emotional and intense.